[Forging Justice]
[Episode 6]
Zheng.
You served
in the military before, right?
Yes.
I heard Court Pres. Zhang
also came over from the military
to take up his post here.
I don't really understand
the professional stuff.
But why do I feel
that Court Pres. Ding
drags his feet too much
when handing down rulings.
Court Pres. Ding is just cautious.
He always reminds us
that there are no small matters in law,
so nothing can be treated carelessly.
We military men
do things decisively.
Get the facts straight,
make a firm decision,
and hand down the ruling
according to the law.
But look at this.
Tried but not sentenced.
Sentenced but not executed.
After months of dragging on,
the public's patience is wearing thin.
Even if they do execute the criminal
in the end,
the impact
will be long gone.
Don't you agree?
I agree.
Which case are you referring to?
What the defense laywer said
is not unreasonable.
These two
maintained this relationship
for nearly 4 years.
During that time, the woman
even wrote love letters to the man.
It's not
entirely out of the question
that it was adultery.
Court Pres. Zhang.
What's your opinion
on this case?
This case...
You guys talk.
I don't know the law,
and I'm new here.
My opinion carries no weight.
Court Pres. Zhang,
you're being way too modest.
You were sent here by the higher-ups
to oversee our work.
So your opinion
matters a lot.
Okay.
Then I'll just speak my mind
for everyone's consideration,
okay?
My opinion is actually very simple.
Two words.
Execute him.
Court Pres. Ding.
If this case
doesn't end with an immediate execution,
do you think
the public
will accept that?
The defendant, Qiao Zhiliang,
using his special status
and
family connections,
employed coercive means
to forcibly engage
in sexual relations with the victim.
His actions
have constituted the crime of rape.
The circumstances of the crime
are egregious,
causing severe harm
to the victim and her family.
The social impact is extremely damaging.
It is indeed
a crime of the utmost severity
and must be punished according to the law.
In accordance with Article 139
of the Criminal Law
of the People's Republic of China,
the defendant, Qiao Zhiliang,
is hereby sentenced to death
and deprived of political rights for life.
Defendant,
you have three days to appeal.
Do you wish to file an appeal?
Take the defendant away.
Court is adjourned.
We need to do something.
Don't stir up more trouble.
Court Pres. Ding has got enough problems.
They said
some Vice Court Pres. Zhang came,
but he's really just an overseer.
He keeps breathing down Ding's neck.
You're actually feeling sorry for Ding?
Cadres indeed always
stick up for one another.
That old Ding Zhongxiang
clearly handed down a ridiculous verdict!
Although it was rape,
it was hardly a capital offense.
You never shut up, do you?
Article 43 of the criminal law states
that the death penalty shall only apply
to criminals
whose crimes are extremely heinous.
For those criminals
who deserve the death penalty,
if immediate execution is not necessary,
they may be given
a suspended death sentence.
In this case,
even if it's a death penalty,
there's no need
for immediate execution, right?
Let's go find Court Pres. Ding.
I, uh...
I just saw the Court Pres. Ding
in his office.
If we go now, we can still catch him.
Let's go!
Let's corner Ding Zhongxiang.
Let's go.
Yu Gaoyuan, are you coming or not?
Of course.
Why wouldn't I?
All of you together?
Sit down.
Please sit down.
Have you eaten?
I just finished eating.
Court Pres. Ding,
we think
the verdict in Qiao Zhiliang's case
is problematic.
You again.
You little rebel.
Court Pres. Ding.
We've all reviewed
Qiao Zhiliang's case.
If...
it's considered adultery,
it might not even warrant
criminal punishment.
If it's considered rape,
it still shouldn't warrant
the death penalty.
Isn't the death penalty
a bit much here?
What do you think
the public's reaction
would be
if we didn't sentence him
to death?
Young lady,
you tell me.
There would be a lot of opposition.
They might even storm the court.
Future trials
might lose all credibility.
That's way too honest.
Look at you.
College students really are different.
That analytical ability
is something else.
Court Pres. Ding,
the law should be rational,
objective,
and principled.
Our rulings
shouldn't be swayed
by public sentiment.
You all make valid points.
But today I am
so exhausted.
From this morning till now,
I haven't had a single bite.
How about
you let me off the hook
for now?
Ding!
Look at this crowd.
Shang.
Come on over.
Have a seat.
Come on.
There are no strangers here.
Have a seat.
Don't stand on ceremony with me.
Why are you all standing?
Sit down. Sit down.
Sit down.
Sit down. Come on.
Ding.
Since I'm here,
I'll keep this short today.
Out of the three death sentences here,
two have already been approved.
Only Qiao Zhiliang's case
has yet to be approved.
For God's sake,
hurry up and get him to file an appeal.
But he refuses to appeal.
If he doesn't appeal,
I have to sit around here
and wait 3 more days.
Then just wait 3 more days.
Shang.
In our Intermediate Court,
how many appeals
have succeeded
and resulted in reversed judgments
this year?
I'll be straight with you.
Zero.
There you go.
Don't you think
our current procedure
is a bit too hasty?
When it's hasty,
mistakes are bound to happen.
It's about a person's life.
You just need to wait 3 more days.
Is that
asking too much?
Alright, alright.
I'll wait. I'll wait, okay?
Ding,
these are
the elite college students
you talked about?
Just look at them.
Every one of them
has got a silver tongue.
They're not to be messed with.
The appeal deadline
used to be within 10 days.
Now it's been shortened to 3.
If an appeal is filed right away,
it gets rejected immediately.
Death penalty cases are somewhat special.
Is this driven
by the demands of the current situation?
Yes.
Dismissal
has almost become the default option.
This leads
to the result you mentioned.
Appealing
actually makes them die faster.
Then why are you
still urging Qiao Zhiliang to appeal?
I want to keep trying.
I think
there is still a glimmer of hope for him.
Are you doing this
for your own unwillingness to let go
or
for the good of your client?
Can you tell the difference?
Qiao Zhiliang's case is different.
I want to see it through to the end.
Even if there's only
a one-in-a-million chance,
I don't want to give up.
Take a seat.
I came here today
to ask you one last time.
Do you still want to appeal?
If you appeal,
I can't guarantee the outcome,
but I will definitely
try my best.
Qiao Zhiliang,
your wife hates you very much,
but she doesn't want you to die either.
She's also doing her best to save you.
For her
and for your two children,
you can't
just give up like this.
Death penalty cases can be appealed.
Please continue to have me
as your lawyer, okay?
During the second trial,
I will definitely
do everything I can for you.
Qiao Zhiliang!
Even I haven't given up on you!
Why are you
giving up on yourself?
Mr. Li.
Thank you for your hard work.
We'll meet again if fate allows.
Li Xiang was just normally
performing his duties
as a defense lawyer.
And for that,
you want to arrest him?
That's not going to look good.
Wait a minute.
Go ahead.
Have some water.
Don't bother.
Don't bother. I'll do it myself.
I'll do it myself.
Have some water. Have some water.
Benshan.
I think the information you just reported
is very good
and very valuable.
But
why didn't you report it
to the organization immediately?
Actually, I did report it.
I reported it to Director Hong.
You even dare to hang up on me now?
If I hadn't taken you in back then,
you would have gone back home
to build reservoirs long ago.
Liang Aimin,
watch your tone!
I'm a regimental‑level officer,
with over 20 years of Party membership,
2 second-class merits,
and 3 third-class merits.
I can shine and contribute
anywhere I go.
And you took me in?
I'm doing this for the sake of our years
as comrades-in-arms.
I'm helping you. Don't you get that?
Right.
Thank you.
And do you know how many times
I've cleaned up your mess?
He supports Li Xiang.
Director Hong
isn't very competent professionally,
and his style of work is rather rough.
I've heard about it.
Besides,
I couldn't bypass my superiors
to report this sort of matter, right?
No matter what,
our Justice Bureau
is still a state‑run institution, right?
What are you afraid of?
What am I afraid of?
Secretary Su called out
your Legal Advisory Office.
I only cursed at you once or twice.
I didn't curse at any leader.
Why did he call me out?
Pleading not guilty is legal, isn't it?
Right.
Isn't a lawyer's diligent defense
a mission and a right
granted to us by law?
Cut the grand talk.
Even if you can't keep up
with the current trend,
you can't go against it, right?
Right now, national incidence rate
of criminal cases
is dropping rapidly.
Public order
has significantly improved.
People's sense of safety
has been enhanced.
At this critical moment,
you argue that a person
sentenced to death is innocent,
and that rape resulting in death
is just a matter of personal conduct.
Do you have any idea
how big a bomb you've dropped?
So before the organization came to you,
what did you do?
I firmly fought against Li Xiang,
but...
But
you weren't firm enough, right?
Secretary Sun.
I... I...
I'm really no match for them.
They've got their little groups
and small factions in the Advisory Office,
so I...
So you just played it safe?
It's okay, Benshan.
We know where you stand.
Otherwise, we wouldn't be
having this conversation today.
Do you understand?
Yes, I understand.
It's about fixing mistakes
before it's too late.
It's fine. Don't worry.
Report what you know
to the organization,
truthfully
and in as much detail as possible.
Because you're the primary witness.
Every word you say
is very valuable.
Okay.
Is it really that serious?
Let me tell you,
don't be ungrateful.
Hurry up and write a self-criticism.
Don't wait
until even I can't protect you anymore.
Then I'll just quit.
You think quitting will solve everything?
Then what?
Are they going to arrest me?
Has it really gotten to the point
where we have to make arrests?
The order has come down,
Court Pres. Ding.
We must act according to the law,
earning the trust of the general public.
Li Xiang
is too young,
immature,
impulsive,
and a bit tactless.
He deserves to be criticized.
I agree that he should write a thorough
self-criticism.
But there's no law stating
that a lawyer
can't disagree
with the procuratorate
or can't plead not guilty, right?
There isn't any legal basis
for arresting him, is there?
He openly defied the organization.
He covered up for the criminal.
He leaked state secrets to the criminal.
Isn't that a violation of the law?
Leaked state secrets?
Yes.
What state secrets
did he leak?
You scared me.
Let me help you.
Thank you.
How come you walk like a cat?
No sound at all.
I used to be a scout.
Who are you looking for?
You.
Me?
I've finished reading
those books you gave me.
I don't have any new ones.
I only brought those textbooks.
I wrote down my thoughts
and did some case analyses.
If you have time,
could you look them over for me?
I'm being a bit inconsiderate
and asking for too much.
Lihui.
Hurry. We're waiting for you.
Jian... Jianmin, why are you here?
Give them to me.
I...
Zheng!
Zheng! Zheng!
Don't leave yet.
How about this?
Help Lihui carry the water upstairs.
We want to talk to you.
Come on. Come on.
Okay.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
Go in.
Have a seat.
What's this about?
Zheng,
you really don't know?
Know what?
This matter
might be a bit serious.
Don't scare him.
What's wrong?
Jianmin,
we're only telling you this
because we trust you.
What is it?
Has Court Pres. Ding said anything to you
about arresting Li Xiang?
Why?
That's impossible.
Jianmin,
has Court Pres. Ding
given you any hints
or...
No.
Even if he really intended
to make an arrest,
he wouldn't tell me.
Arrests
should be the police's job.
Why would they need Court Pres. Ding
for that?
So we
want you to do some digging internally.
Over the next few days,
try to get some information
out of Court Pres. Ding
and see if it's true.
If it is true,
we need to prepare in advance.
It will be too late
once things get rolling.
Jianmin,
we've always had
a good relationship.
I've always considered you a friend.
Besides, Li Xiang really is a good guy.
He shouldn't become
a martyr for this case.
You want me...
To put it bluntly,
we want you
to be a spy for us.
That doesn't sound good.
It should be
a sharp knife
thrust into the enemy's heart.
But Court Pres. Ding isn't the enemy.
Isn't he?
What's so funny?
Fine.
Even if I find out
that they are indeed going to arrest him,
what do you plan to do?
Chen Yizhong.
Are you going to tell him in advance
so that he can abscond?
Talk him into resisting arrest?
Or be his defense lawyer?
Or
stage protests?
File petitions?
Storm the judicial authorities?
Or throw rotten eggs
and tomatoes at him
during the trial?
Come on,
how could you be like this?
Like what?
You want me to be your spy.
I work for the court.
I should just throw my job away?
And you don't want
your internship reports either?
In a few months,
you'll go back to Beijing.
Will you take me, this sharp knife,
with you?
Or just leave me
in the enemy's heart?
No, Jianmin.
We're not doing this
for ourselves.
We want to help Li Xiang.
For the progress of China's legal system,
we want to do some...
This proposition...
I know
you guys are very kind
and passionate.
You also have a strong sense of justice.
But it's inappropriate
to make groundless accusations
about this kind of thing.
I won't tell anyone
what was said in this room today.
Wait.
Jianmin, could you...
Lihui.
Next time you need water,
let the guys carry it.
Zheng Jianmin.
I'm sorry.
You don't need to apologize.
I'm quite regretful.
I was a bit harsh just now.
It's nothing.
I think we needed
that reality check from your words.
It's a good thing.
I'm sorry.
Zhang Lihui, you know what?
Out of the five of you,
I think you stand out the most.
If you said
I'm the easiest to get along with,
I'd believe that.
Stand out the most...
Don't underestimate me.
I'm not casually praising you
just because you lent me
a few books.
I'm used
to being polite with people,
but I don't genuinely praise others
very often.
I don't mean anything else by it.
I just feel that the two of us
are quite similar in some ways.
I really didn't expect you
to see me that way.
Yeah,
we are quite similar.
Reading the room.
Staying ahead of things.
Trying to take care of others' feelings.
Considerate and easygoing.
I have to do this
because of my work.
I don't know what you've been through,
but I get you,
just like I get myself.
Actually,
you've got quite a mind of your own.
You also know how to get things done.
Your resilience
runs deep inside you.
Really?
I didn't even know that myself.
About this matter,
I'll ask around,
but I can't guarantee any results.
If I find anything out,
I'll only tell you.
Why?
For the progress of China's legal system.
Do you believe it?
Zheng Jianmin.
I feel like
I'm only getting to know you today.
Is that a compliment or an insult?
A compliment, of course.
After I tell you what I find out,
who you choose to tell
is none of my business.
Got it?
Got it.
Thank you.
How is this leaking any kind
of state secret?
They're a bunch of legal illiterates.
Come in.
Court Pres. Ding.
Court Pres. Ding, please don't bother.
I'm not thirsty.
That won't do.
Napoleon once said
that you are hens that lay golden eggs.
How can I let our hens suffer?
I'm here as an intern,
so I'm your subordinate.
Besides, I'm male.
I can't lay eggs.
What brings you to me?
Li Xiang's performance record.
What do you mean?
Court Pres. Ding.
Last year,
Li Xiang handled
36 cases in total.
Among them, 19 were criminal cases,
including 15 appointed defenses.
He argued for lighter sentences
in all of them.
The other 17 were civil cases,
with a mediation success rate
as high as 70%.
In 10 of those cases,
he didn't charge any fees.
So?
What does this prove?
It obviously proves that Li Xiang
is a very good lawyer.
He's dedicated,
earnest, professional,
and well‑respected.
Court Pres. Ding.
I heard that because Li Xiang
pleaded not guilty for Qiao Zhiliang,
someone wants to arrest him.
Who told you that?
Saying something like that
comes with consequences!
Tell me!
Who told you it?
Nobody told me.
I passed by your office a few days ago
and accidentally overheard it.
Accidentally?
Overheard it?
You didn't leave
and listened to the whole thing.
From the perspective of criminal elements,
was there any criminal intent?
Court Pres. Ding, I was wrong.
I'll accept
any criticism from you,
but I think
Li Xiang has done nothing wrong.
Zheng, come here!
You wrote down
19 criminal cases here.
As the court president,
I can tell you
that his success rate in defense
is less than 10%.
How is that professional?
You also wrote
that he received 3 complaints
within a single year!
Is that what you call well-respected?
Court Pres. Ding,
given the current social climate,
a 10% success rate in criminal defense
is already
pretty good.
As for those 3 complaints,
two of them were because
he defended the bad guys.
That proves nothing.
Protecting the legitimate rights
and interests of the client
is a lawyer's statutory duty.
If he believes Qiao Zhiliang is innocent
but doesn't bring it up,
that's a dereliction of his duty.
The court can accept
his defense arguments
or reject them.
But he shouldn't be arrested
just because his opinion
differs from the prosecution, right?
Are you done?
No.
Go on.
The state is now promoting
reforms in political and legal work.
I think Nanyu is fortunate
to have a lawyer
like Li Xiang.
If we treat him like this,
Court Pres. Ding,
lawyers in court will truly become
nothing more than decorations
in the future.
Come in!
Court Pres. Ding, you wanted to see me?
Tell the General Services Department
to replace this door!
It's letting in drafts!
Yes.
Go on.
Not bad this time.
Very impressive.
I see you in a new light now.
Don't give me that.
But wasn't it a bit reckless?
You should have discussed it
with us first,
so we could all go together.
Not reckless at all.
I thought it through before I went.
I'm the team leader for this internship.
My talk with Court Pres. Ding
was an organization-to-organization
conversation.
If you guys had showed up,
wouldn't it have turned
into a mob gathering,
just like last time?
But aren't you worried?
What if you really offended
Court Pres. Ding,
and he writes a bad review
on your internship appraisal?
Then I'll make sure
he has no choice but to acknowledge me.
If we really
manage to save Li Xiang this time,
we'll have a real achievement.
After returning to Beijing,
our job assignments will be secure.
What happened
when you went home this time?
You haven't told me yet.
Nothing happened.
I've simply
had some new thoughts
about my future career plans.
What new thoughts?
Just
pragmatism,
utilitarianism,
and results-oriented thinking?
Comrade Xia Yingjie,
I don't think
pragmatism is a derogatory term.
Achieving one's goals
within legal and reasonable bounds
strikes me as wisdom.
I don't want
my future career
to be full of compromises
and people pulling my strings.
I want to stay at the Supreme People's Court
and the Supreme People's Procuratorate.
Let's
stay in Beijing together.
Let's stay in Beijing together.
Come over.
I heard
Qiu Agui is going to be executed,
right?
Yes.
The public sentencing rally is tomorrow.
This time,
could you postpone the execution?
I want to check how arrangements
are coming along for her children.
I want to make sure
her three children are taken care of
as best as possible,
so she can go to her death
with peace of mind.
I know
this case weighs heavily
on your mind,
but don't forget
the case is closed.
This is the outcome.
Whether you can let it go or not,
you have to let it go.
Yes.
And there is absolutely no need for you
to have further contact
with the convict.
Actually, I'm doing this
for myself.
I want to be able
to sleep more peacefully.
I can't call off the execution,
but I can postpone it
for a few days.
Alright then.
I'll take her off this batch
and move her to the next one, okay?
Will that do?
Thank you, Ding.
I went to visit your family yesterday.
Your wife has forgiven you.
Please tell her
to forget me
and never
let the children know
that they have a father like me.
Tomorrow is the last day
of the appeal period.
I hope you'll make one last effort
for yourself, alright?
You don't have to do anything.
Just give your consent
and keep me as your lawyer.
I'll handle the rest.
That's all.
I killed Wei Sanmei.
I ruined her.
How could I have any face left
to go on living?
I deserve to be shot!
I deserve to die.
Why are you here?
I don't believe it.
I don't believe it either,
so I sent Yu
to ask Court Pres. Ding.
Then what did he say?
He didn't give a clear answer.
I think it's most likely true.
Even if it is,
what can I do?
Thank you for telling me.
I'll pretend I never heard it.
I'll just eat, sleep,
and do whatever I need to do.
Well...
Is there anything
we can do for you?
You guys?
I'm a straightforward
person.
Forget it. Forget it.
Wait...
If you get arrested,
who will defend you?
Probably no one.
In Nanyu County,
there are only 3 lawyers in total.
Wang Benshan
and Qin Zhigao.
One won't defend me,
and the other
can't defend at all.
Let me defend you.
You?
You don't have a lawyer's license.
I can still be
your lay defender.
I know you think
we college students are overly ambitious,
impulsive, and naive,
right?
But I'm still better than Wang Benshan,
Think about it.
Okay.
Then I'll take you
as my lay defender.
Okay.
Sign a power of attorney.
Do you have any paper here?
Don't touch my bag.
It's full of Qiao Zhiliang's case files.
Come back to the Advisory Office with me.
I'll sign it in my office.
What if you can't make it back?
That won't happen, right?
How about this?
Write it on my vest.
Write it here.
Are you two okay?
Yes.
Push harder.
Are you okay?
Come on.
We're almost there.
Xia,
are you okay?
If you're feeling unwell,
just wait here.
Director Xiang.
Those whose parents are dead
are considered orphans.
And for orphans,
every region has its own policies.
The civil affairs department
will provide child support
based on the local
average living standard.
In this way,
the 3 children
will have their basic needs covered,
right?
In the village,
there are plenty of unattended children.
That's not the way to look at it.
These 3 children have no parents.
If the state doesn't take care of them,
how are they going to grow up?
If they go astray later in life,
won't that just be more problems
for the state?
I have one more suggestion.
Have the brigade hold and manage
the money.
When it's needed,
their grandmother can come to the brigade
to collect it.
This provides dual protection.
You not only handle the cases,
but also take care of things
for the convicts after they're gone.
Qiu Agui is truly fortunate
to have met someone like you.
Liang, wait a moment.
Come in.
Court Pres. Ding.
Zhang, come in.
Please take the measurements first.
What's this about?
I was thinking we don't have enough money
to replace the door.
We could just patch up the gaps
and reinforce the old door.
Replace the door?
Why would I want to replace the door
for no reason?
Yesterday, didn't you tell me
to replace...
Get out.
Close the door!
Yes.
Liang, please continue.
What?
Arresting Li Xiang is absurd enough.
Now they want to catch Hong Zhansheng too?
Zhang, are you busy?
The review
for Qiao Zhiliang's death penalty
has been approved.
Did you know that?
The county
is holding a public sentencing rally.
They're adding Qiu Agui and another one
to make it three,
like the Peach Garden Oath.
Those three will all be executed
after the sentencing.